hey hey what's up my friend so in this
video I'm going to show you or reveal to
you my trading results from my own live
trading account from Interactive Broker
right so you will see the equity curve
right not just based on you know one two
three four five trades but rather the
full year 2024 on how my trading results
have performed and also I want to share
with you some of my biggest lessons that
I've learned in
2024 and
surprisingly some of the lessons come
from the crypto market right where you
will learn how to actually find higher
probability trading setups and better
time your entry let's
go okay so this is my first trading
account as you can see over here I just
kind of put this account one and the
result is for 2024 from January all the
way to December you can see that uh this
account up about 29% right uh during
this period
and another account okay I'll explain to
you shortly why I have multiple accounts
right so this one let's call it account
to again for 2024 from January all the
way to December 31st this account is up
about
50% now some of you might be thinking
but right now you know in 2024 it's a
bull market anyone can make money I
agree fair point so let me walk you
through my account since Inception which
is I think since 2019 okay so we'll take
into account Co the Russia Ukraine war
the spike of interest rates and let's
see so back to account one again you can
see this is the equ curve of account one
total return so far about 123% as of
February 133 here one day before
Valentine's Day maybe Valentine's Day
right might have a breakout right so who
knows yeah anyway uh uh this is uh
account one you can see that the equity
curve right it's relatively nice move
and consistent right and the reason for
this is that the strategy the system
that I employ for this account is more
of a mean reversion trading system so
the idea behind it is that I'm not
looking to write Trends I'm just looking
to capture a swing to take one move out
of the market so for example a typical
trading setup will look something like
this Market is in an uptrend it makes a
pullback I'll buy and then when it has a
slight bounce I'm going to sell capture
it one move so this is uh the result of
this uh system for this account the
other one account two you can see over
here the equity curve is very different
this one in this instance you can see
that it's a lot more volatile you can
see the market goes up you know goes
sideways then Spike up right then here
goes sideway for a while goes under
water and now we Spike up again up about
190% close to 200% uh since 2019 so you
can see that this system that I employ
is a more of a I won't call it high R
but the volatility of returns is is much
higher right because this is a Trend
following system right we pretty much
buy uh stocks that are strong right and
we write the trend up higher and we have
no idea how high it can go so sometimes
when it reverse down you know it hits
our trailing stop loss right we can give
back a huge chunk of open profit so this
is why the volatility of this uh system
is higher compared to the earlier one
and the reason why I trade this on
different accounts just simply for
tracking purposes I can see which system
at a glance right is how is it
performing over time right and when I
separate things out it's a lot more
clearer compared to you know trading mod
multiple systems in one account it will
kind of like you know clout uh the data
that's why I have multiple systems
across multiple
accounts okay next let me share with you
some of the biggest trading lessons that
I've learned in 2024 be surprised right
I've been trading for 10 over years and
there still you know so many things to
learn each and every year so first thing
first seasonality can be useful and I
learned this actually from the crypto
markets yeah so I have been aware of
seasonality all along but I just just
didn't know know how to kind of make use
of this number so crypto Market is where
I really gain Enlightenment over here so
let me walk you through what is season
seasonality in case some of you are not
aware of it so seasonality right
generally what it tries to do is that to
see I mean you can break this up into
many different ways but for this one
that I'm sharing over here over here you
can see that what is the
average returns of an asset class each
month from January February all the way
to December and if you look at Bitcoin
this Bitcoin over here you can see uh
one thing that stands out is that
October is generally a very good month
for Bitcoin why is that it's anyone's
guess maybe you know towards the year
end R people are feeling optimistic
festive season is coming they bullish
whatever the case sometimes could even
be uh the Hing effect right you know
2016 202 2024 so might probably think
what is the Haring effect so usually uh
every four years Bitcoin the the the the
miners the block be cut in half so the
supply of Bitcoin getss decreased every
four years when Supply gets reduced
price tends to go up so that's what we
call the haling effect but again you can
Google and learn more about it but for
now we're talking about seasonalities
you look at Bitcoin generally in October
right uh it's pretty bullish right you
can see that the average return is about
21% median return about 21% as well if
you look at November pretty bullish as
well okay median return is lower but the
average return is about
46 right so this means that hey you know
uh the
if it's a bullish year it could really
get pretty crazy right in November
that's why the average is higher than a
median and if you look at December uh
may just I say it's May right so if you
look through the the data you can see
that yeah October November Bitcoin right
have pretty strong uh average and median
return so how can this information be
useful for you so now they you know this
seasonality pattern of Bitcoin and by
the way it doesn't have to be applied to
bitcoin only can be applied to you know
Commodities or whatever Market you're
trading if you can get the seasonality
in this case I got the seasonality data
from coin glass you know you can use
this and overlay with your technical
analysis your own trading setup so so
follow along with me so right now you
know that October November okay you know
Bitcoin tends to be uh strong in those
months so now let's have a look at a
Bitcoin chart okay so I just plot this
chart of Bitcoin and we know that okay
October November it tends to be bullish
period for Bitcoin is there a valid
trading setup so if you look back you
know I just kind of go back over here
you can see over here on
November 2024 this this on 6 November
2024 we actually had a breakout over
here okay so this is the the resistance
right and then over here we had a
breakout so
maybe you know you look at this chart
you know you realize oh there's a
breakout you're thinking know should I
buy or not no you know some think the
price is really high you know could it
even go any higher but then you overl
seasonality and you realize oh during
this period you know October November
the price of Bitcoin tends to know
do really well so this can gives you an
added confirmation to your technical
trading setup to give you that
confidence boost right to place that
trade so this is how seasonality can
help you how should I put it find high
probability trading setup so this is
just one example of a trading setup you
know who knows your other setups could
be like a breakout and retest something
like this let's say you know uh let's
say for example let's say there's a
breakout and Bitcoin does a retest and
they got rejection like a hammer and
then you think should I take this tra if
the seasonality during this period tends
to be bullish yeah all the more you want
to be excited for this trade because not
only the technical or the trading setup
is valid but you also have this
seasonality pattern that you know backs
it up yeah so this is how you can use
seasonality to help you uh find higher
probability trades and you know better
time your
entry now one thing to caution is that
you know seasonality is not a
concept or strategy that you want to
trade on its own because seasonality
itself right doesn't give you a
predefined entry point you know where
they set your stop loss targets Etc so
this is where technical analysis you
know comes into play it's useful because
technical analysis can Define right
pretty accurately you know where to
enter exit and set your stop loss so
just a word of warning don't trade
seasonality on it so maybe you know
let's say you know you know Bitcoin is
bullish during October November but what
if those months it doesn't play out the
way you expect and it reverse against
you where you going to cut your cut your
loss right you're going to wait for one
month by the time you know the price
could know reverse strongly against you
so this is where you know ta technical
analysis helps right to help you
predefine your entries and exits and by
the way if you enjoyed you know uh such
lessons and you one more tip bits right
you can actually subscribe to my
newsletter where every week I send out
actionable trading tips just like this I
can go down to my website trading with
r.com over here okay and then just feel
free right I have three guides over here
for you to download is free right for
example you can download the essential
guide to systems trading right where you
learn more about systematic trading and
also each week I'll send send you
actionable trading tips right that you
can use to improve your trading results
right so yeah check it out right if it
helps now moving
on okay lesson number two beware of
extreme sentiments in the market all
right so so here's the thing right you
know I am not the perfect Trader I
myself you know have feelings of foro
fear and stuff like that so actually you
can see over here I had this feeling of
four more over here right so I was
posting this in actually one of the
crypto uh Facebook group right so
virtual virtual is actually the the the
protocol right call it token or the
ticker whatever you want to call it
right so you can see that this this this
sticker or this uh token right is
performing really well right virtual you
can see right it's from like what don't
know a few cents they kind of speack up
all the way to $5 right so I wasn't in
this trade so this is why I said I was
sideline over here means I'm not in this
I feel for more right because this is
like virtually Unstoppable right so you
can imagine if I'm feeling this way it
means that the sentiments of this uh
token is really bullish at this point in
time right so I'm not the only one
feeling this I'm pretty sure a lot of
Traders or crypto investors are feeling
this way as well and then guess what
happened
next boom my that post pretty much
nailed the top I pretty much I didn't
call the top right but that post when it
came up right it means that the top is
pretty much near already so this is
where I share beware of extreme
sentiments beware when there's voices in
new saying that W man look at this chart
man how juicy this is oh you know you
know look at how e is it to make money
it's going to go up you know for the
foreseeable future for sure that is
where the alarm should start ringing
ding ding right that hey you know
warning signs right is the market could
be topage right and looking to make a a
a pullback or reversal still I agree
that you know what's high can go higher
that's how Trend followers make money so
so this where again technical analysis
Trading
techniques right will be useful over
here if you want to trade a market
that's trending up higher so for example
let's go back to the earlier chart over
here trending up like this over here
okay but at the same time you know ra
say beware of extreme sentiments right
because the market can be topish so how
do you that enter such trade so one way
to go about is you know look to buy on a
pullback look to trade when there a
valid trading setup so this way you can
know exactly where you're going to enter
and where to cut your loss if you are
wrong and that's so important right so
so again looking back now if you want to
trade a chart like this where sentiment
is really bullish but there's a
possibility of further upside or what's
high can go higher yeah so how you can
do is for example wait for a valid
trading set up like for example like
this right Market maybe makes a pullback
and it goes to a range it retest this
lows and then gives you a bullish price
rejection maybe like a a hammer
something like this now Market can be
bullish but if you have this valid
trading setup you can enter over here
and you know set your stop loss and
distance below this low this way your
risk is kep right even if the market
were to reverse against you and hit your
stop loss guess what you really can
determine right where to get up when
you're wrong compared to know let's say
chasing the market at this High let's
say the market is at this High you buy
over here where are you going to set
your stop loss there's no reference
logical points on the chart to set your
stop loss if you want to if you ask me
you know maybe this might be a close one
right over here where previous you know
uh swing high or resistance which could
become Support over here okay and you
can see that the distance actually
pretty far down yeah so and who's to say
that the market couldn't retest this
level over here to find support so you
can see that you know when you want to
set your stop loss in this example you
know your stop loss are usually very
wide which means that you know you have
to risk giving back pretty huge chunk of
open profits or profits right to see how
this trade plays out yeah so lesson
number two is this right beware of
extreme sentiments whether the sentiment
is extremely bullish or extremely
bearish right it's always like if that
inner voice of you feel oh man you know
it's definitely moving in this direction
yeah beware that's a that's a sign that
hey the market could be reversing right
that doesn't mean that you can trade it
right but please right trade it with a
valid trading setup so this way you have
a proper stop loss to cap your
downside number three data gives you
confidence now here's the thing right
there are so many different trading
strategies methods systems out there but
still most Traders fail I can dare say
you know out of 100 that attempts to be
a Trader 90% won't make it after 2 or 3
years why is that if you ask me there
are two main reasons
first your trading strategy your system
doesn't work that's why no matter how
disciplined you are in following the
rules it's not going to matter at all
it's like going after a girl if the girl
doesn't like you at all no matter what
you do how many gifts you buy for her
how sweet you are to her how thoughtful
you are for her to her it's not going to
matter she doesn't like you means that's
it if you're friend zone that's it okay
you can't move an immovable object and
it's the same thing for trading if you
don't have a trading system that work
your trading account the equity curve
it's not going to move up higher instead
it probably go down low lower after
taking into account transaction cost and
and whatnot so firstly you need to have
a trading system that works and the
reason why most Traders fail is because
they just don't have that second thing
is this even if you have a trading
system that
works you will start to doubt it right
when the losses come right maybe after
five losing trades in a row 7 eight
losing trades in a row you start to
wonder man rer you know has the trading
system stopped working man R did I do
something wrong you know and and you
just don't have confidence in yourself
and in the trading system
so how can you then overcome this
problem this is where you know data
comes in because if you have the data
the
numbers the facts behind your trading
system how much more confident will you
be so for example if you look at this
data over here so this is a a trading
system right that I'm about to release
in my new book trading systems that work
the book is not available yet but you
can see that this system right I can
share with you the exact numbers behind
this system right you can see from 1995
all the way to 2023 you can see that the
yearly returns right like for example
1995 made 72% 2023 up % 2022 lost close
to 20% you can see that the average
winning rate is about 57% you can see
that the average profit percentage for
each trade is about 46% you can see that
the average loss for each trade is about
10% these numbers this data gives you
confidence right so if you to trade this
system for example let's say if you to
trade this
system and you are in a draw down maybe
you're having a one two or three losing
months you can look back historically
and see Ah that's not too uncommon right
over here you know losing periods you
know two months in a row yeah here as
well not too uncommon or maybe here over
here 15% you know drop for this given
month right so if in future you have
like a 10% loss in a given month you
know that this is something that has
happened before so this gives you
confidence to continuously follow the
rules of this trading system and if you
can have an equity curve of a system
that looks like that this gives you
confidence right knowing that hey you
know whenever the system goes into a
draw down right draw down meaning loses
money right maybe due to unfavorable
Market maret condition draw down draw
down draw down it always you know break
out to new alltime High so draw down it
breaks out to this new high over here
new high over here new high over here
yeah so this would instill confidence in
you to continuously trade the system so
this is why personally I feel that data
data gives you confidence you need to
have data behind your trading system and
that's how you kind of like you know
take your trading to the next level okay
and by the way if you have enjoyed this
video so far maybe you to learn more
about trading in a way that you can have
confidence you can just again just go
down to my website trading freer.com
grabb a copy of this book uh the
essential guide to systems trading we'll
talk about how you can actually develop
your own trading system so you have data
right to back your decisions and of
course I'll send you know actionable
trading tips every single week so you
can level up your trading right sounds
good then go and grab a copy it's free
and I will talk to you soon